杀死它了吗？
Did that kill it?
没有
No.
我们要那样杀它
That's how we kill it.
维山帝之书
The Book of Vishanti!
不能让它夺走你的能力 快去拿书
We can't let it take your power. Get to the book.
要怎么过去？
How do we get across?
跳
Jump.
抓紧
Hold on!
不…
No, no, no!
它威力太强了
It's too strong.
我撑不住
I can't hold it.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
这是唯一的办法
This is the only way.
你在做什么？
What're you doing?
我不能让那怪物夺走你的能力
I can't let that thing take your power.
你控制不了它
You can't control it.
但我可以
But I can.
我们是朋友
But we're friends.
你会杀死我
You're killing me.
我知道
I know.
但在多重宇宙的庞大计算里
But in the grand calculus of the Multiverse...
你牺牲的价值超过你的…
your sacrifice is worth more than your...
借过
Excuse me. May I?
谢谢
Thanks.
斯特兰奇医师
Doctor Strange.
韦斯特医师
Doctor West.
有一阵子没见了
Haven't seen you in a while.
我有五年变成尘埃
Yeah, I was a little preoccupied being dust there for five years, so...
很多人也是
So were a lot of us.
我不在的时候…
While I was gone...
谢谢关心
thank you for asking...
我失去了两只猫
I lost both my cats...
和我弟弟
and my brother.
很遗憾
I'm very sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚上睡不着时我常在想
I guess what keeps me up at night is wondering...
非得那样惨烈不可吗？
did it have to happen that way?
有没有别的路可行？
Was there any other path?
没有
No.
我用了仅有的方法
No, I made the only play we had.
那当然
Well, of course you did.
一流外科医师又是最棒的超级英雄
The best surgeon and the best superhero.
但你还是没掳获佳人芳心
But you still didn't get the girl.
麻烦一杯红酒
Glass of red, please.
我来效劳 小姐
Oh, allow me, miss.
太没创意了？
Little too on the nose?
你 在我婚礼上？
What? For you, at my wedding?
不 我觉得很完美
Nah. I think it was perfect.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
查理来了
There's Charlie.
介绍你认识 因为他…
I have to introduce you because he's kind of...
有点丢脸 他是铁粉
It's embarrassing, but he's a big fan, so...
克里斯汀
Hey, Christine.
我应该…
I should've...
真希望当初不是那样
I wish I'd have been different.
我始终关心着我们俩
I never stopped caring about us.
但我必须做出牺牲…
But I had to make sacrifices...
才能保护你
to protect you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们之间根本不可能
It was never gonna work out between us.
为什么？
Why not?
因为 史蒂芬
Because, Stephen...
你非得掌控一切不可
you have to be the one holding the knife.
我一向尊重你 却无法因此爱你
And I always respected you for it, but I couldn't love you for it.
这句话你忍了多久？
How long you had that one in the barrel?
很久了
Long time.
我想也是
Yeah. I bet.
听着
Look...
我真的很高兴你找到幸福
Truly, I'm just glad that you're happy.
我很幸福
I am.
真的很幸福
I really, really am.
那就好
Good.
你呢？
Are you?
我很幸福
I'm happy.
那就好
Good.
你值得幸福
You deserve it.
小心 那是什么？
Oh, man. Look out! What is that?
老兄
Dude!
谢谢
Thank you.
哇
Wow!
不
No, no.
小心
Look out!
我认识你吗？
Do I know you?
救命啊
Help!
别客气
You're welcome.
知道向至尊魔法师鞠躬是古老习俗吗
You know it's ancient custom to bow in the presence of the Sorcerer Supreme?
我懂习俗
Yeah, I'm aware of the customs.
撑住
Hold it, hold it!
不可思议
That's incredible.
是啊
Yeah.
天啊
Oh, God!
她是谁？
Who's this?
我正想问同样的问题
Yeah, I was gonna ask the same question.
小鬼
Hey, kid.
那只怪兽为什么要追你？
What did that creature want with you?
你父母呢？
Where're your parents?
我们送她回…
We'll take her back to the...
她拿走我的悬戒
She took my Slingie.
她拿走你的悬戒
She took your Slingie.
太夸张了
Yeah, it was crazy, man.
天啊
Oh, my God!
我不会杀你 小鬼
I'm not gonna kill you, kid.
我拼了命想救你 记得吗？
I just bust my ass trying to save your life, remember?
巨兽我能对付
Giant monsters I can clearly handle...
困扰我的是昨晚你出现在我梦里
but what bothers me is that last night, you were in my dream.
那不是梦
That wasn't a dream.
那是另一个宇宙
It was another universe.
你们有多少多重宇宙的经验？
How much experience do you guys have with the Multiverse?
我们有多重宇宙的经验
We have experience of the Multiverse.
最近有件事与蜘蛛侠有关
Most recently, there was an incident with Spider-Man.
什么人？
What man?
-蜘蛛侠 他有蜘蛛的超能力　-所以叫蜘蛛侠
-Spider-Man. He has the powers of a spider. -Hence the name.
好恶心
Gross.
他长得像蜘蛛吗？
Does he look like a spider?
不 比较像人
No. No, more like a man.
爬墙 射蜘蛛网
Climbs walls, shoots webs.
-答对了　-从屁股射吗？
-Yeah. Bingo. -Out of his butt?
不是　-不是
-No. -No.
也许吧 我也不知道
Well, maybe, I don't know.
我真心希望不是
Honestly, I hope not.
超诡异
Super weird.
这样吃会肚子痛
You're gonna get a stomach ache.
我来自另一个宇宙
I'm from another universe.
你怎么知道我的肚子跟你一样？
How do you know my stomach works the same as yours?
不知道
I don't.
我根本不知道你是否来自另一个宇宙
I don't even know if you're from another universe...
所以我还坐在这里等你开示
which is why I'm still sitting here, waiting for you to enlighten us.
我不得不说
Gotta say,
目前我见过的两个奇异博士
of the two Doctor Stranges I've met so far...
你不是我最喜欢的
you're not my favorite.
什么意思？
Which means?
他不懂西班牙语吗？
Does he not know Spanish?
我连他爱不爱说英语都不清楚
I'm not sure he even enjoys speaking English.
我离开一场美丽的婚礼
Look, I left a very nice wedding...
去救一个小屁孩 以免她被章鱼吃掉
to save a smart-ass kid from getting eaten by an octopus.
-谁的婚礼？　-克里斯汀
-Whose wedding? -Now tell me... Christine's.
-你去了？　-靠 你娶了克里斯汀？
-You went? -Holy shit, you married Christine?
-能拍照吗？　-不能
-Do you mind? -Yes, I do.
我没有 对
No, I didn't. Yes.
你得跟我解释怎么回事
You need to explain to me what's going on.
那只章鱼为什么想吃你？
Why was that octopus trying to eat you?
那怪物想绑架我
That thing was trying to kidnap me.
它就像恶魔的爪牙
It's like a henchman who works for a demon.
我们只知道他们想夺走我的能力
All we knew is that they wanted to take my power for themselves.
什么能力？
What power?
我能在多重宇宙间旅行
I can travel the Multiverse.
什么？
What?
你能在不同宇宙间移动？
You can physically move from one universe to another?
怎么做？
How?
问题就是我不知道
That's the problem. I don't know how.
我无法控制它
Can't control it.
只有在我非常害怕时才有办法
Only happens when I'm really, really afraid.
我的分身能击败这个恶魔吗？
Okay. And did Other Me know how to defeat this demon?
你们知道一本纯良魔法书
Well, you guys knew of this magical book of pure good...
它给魔法师击败敌人所需的指引
that gives a sorcerer whatever they need to defeat their enemy.
维山帝之书？
The Book of Vishanti?
那不是真的
It's not real.
那是神话 不存在
It's a fairy tale. It doesn't exist.
其实它存在
Actually, it does.
成为至尊魔法师时拿到的秘笈中有写
I found out in the secret book you get when you become Sorcerer Supreme.
不可思议
Unbelievable.
你不是至尊魔法师？
You're not the Sorcerer Supreme?
我不是至尊魔法师
No, I'm not the Sorcerer Supreme.
你的分身是他那个宇宙的至尊魔法师
Other You was Sorcerer Supreme of his universe.
是
Right. Yeah.
虽然它存在
Although it does exist...
维山帝之书据说无法取得
the Book of Vishanti is said to be unreachable.
没错 只是…
It is. Except...
我们取得了
we reached it.
结果那个恶魔追上我们
Then the demon caught up with us.
我以为你会保护我 可是…
I thought you'd protect me...
你没有
but you didn't.
那是我梦中的那场打斗
That was the fight in my dream.
那不是梦
That wasn't a dream.
证明给我看
Prove it.
那不是梦
It wasn't a dream.
这表示…
That means...
梦是窥探多重宇宙自我的窗口
dreams are windows into the lives of our Multiversal selves.
那是他的理论
That was his theory.
所以我裸体被小丑追的恶梦…
So, that recurring nightmare where I'm running naked from a clown...
在某个地方是真的
Somewhere out there, it's real.
我在那个地方绑马尾
Somewhere out there I had a ponytail.
可能会有更多怪兽来追杀她
There could be more creatures coming for her.
这能力在小鬼手中就够危险了
The power is dangerous enough in the hands of a kid.
要是被真正的威胁取得呢？
Imagine if a real threat acquired it?
对了 年轻人 我们不知道你名字
It occurs to me, young one, we don't know your name.
阿美莉卡查维兹
America Chavez.
查小姐 愿意跟我们到卡玛泰姬吗？
Miss Chavez, will you come with us to Kamar-Taj?
你在那里会很安全
You'll be safe there.
我怎么知道你不会跟他一样背叛我？
How do I know you won't betray me like he did?
我想你只能相信我了
I guess you're just gonna have to trust me.
该拿他怎么办？
What do we do with him?
这样违反规定
That's gotta violate an ordinance.
我埋过更糟的
Ah, I've buried worse.
杀死他的怪兽…
The creature that killed him...
有跟那只章鱼一样的记号吗？
did it have the same markings as the octopus?
卢恩符文
Runes.
这不是魔法
This isn't sorcery.
是巫术
It's witchcraft.
有谁面对过这种东西吗？
Do we know anyone who's faced such a thing?
我可能知道
I think I might.
巧克力
Chocolate!
我说什么？
Hey! What did I say?
我们等不及了
But we couldn't wait.
我怎么说的？
But what did I say?
去洗手
Go wash your hands.
妈 别这样 我们年纪太大了
Mom, come on. We're too old for that.
好吧
Oh, okay.
你能帮我盖被子 妈
You can tuck me in, Mom.
没问题
I will.
你知道 家人是永远的
You know, a family is forever.
就算想 我们也不可能真的离开彼此
We could never truly leave each other, even if we tried.
妈 我改变心意了
Mom, I changed my mind.
你要的话可以帮我盖被子
You can come tuck me in if you want.
好
Okay.
爱你
Love you.
苹果 对吧？
Apples, right?
最后会长出来
Eventually.
-闻起来…　-香甜
-Smells... -Sweet.
我想说真实
I was gonna say real.
千真万确 谢谢
It's all very real, thanks.
我已经不碰魔法了
I've put the magic behind me.
看得出来
So I can see.
我知道你迟早会出现
Well, I knew sooner or later you'd show up...
想讨论西景镇发生的事
wanting to discuss what happened at Westview.
我犯了错 人们受到伤害
I made mistakes, and people were hurt...
但你最后拨乱反正 这点无庸置疑
But you put things right in the end, and that was never in doubt.
我不是来谈西景镇的
I'm not here to talk about Westview.
那你来做什么？
Then what are you here for?
我们需要你帮忙
We need your help.
帮什么忙？
With what?
你了解多重宇宙吗？
What do you know about the Multiverse?
多重宇宙
The Multiverse.
幻视有他的一套理论
Vis had his theories.
他认为那是真的 而且很危险
He believed it was real, and dangerous.
这两点他都说对了
Well, he was right about both.
我们发现一个能在其中移动的女孩
We found a girl who can somehow travel across it...
但有人在追杀她
but she's being pursued.
-谁？　-某种恶魔
-Pursued by who? -Some kind of demon.
觊觎她的能力
One that covets her power for itself.
我们带她去卡玛泰姬 虽然能自卫
We've taken her to Kamar-Taj, and we've got our defenses...
但我们用得上一个复仇者
but we could use an Avenger.
还有其他复仇者
There are other Avengers.
对 在留庞克头的弓箭手
Yeah, but given the choice between the archer with the mohawk...
几个与昆虫同名的打击犯罪高手
and several bug-themed crime fighters...
或是全球最强大的魔法师之间抉择
or one of the most powerful magic-wielders on the planet...
答案显而易见
it's an easy call.
到卡玛泰姬来
Come to Kamar-Taj.
你又能被印在便当盒上了
It'll get you back on the lunch box.
要是你带阿美莉卡过来呢？
What if you brought America here?
来这里？
Here?
我了解孤单无助
Yeah. I know what it's like to be on your own...
因天生的能力而遭猎杀的滋味
hunted for abilities you never wanted...
我能保护她
and I can protect her.
-你还没说她的名字吧？　-没有
-You never told me her name, did you? -No.
我没说
No, I didn't.
咒圈不难应付
You know, the Hex was the easy part.
难的是说谎
The lying, not so much.
黑暗神书
The Darkhold.
你熟悉黑暗神书？
You're familiar with the Darkhold?
我知道它是死亡之书
I know it's the Book of the Damned...
接触到它的一切都会堕入邪恶
and that it corrupts everything and everyone that it touches.
不知道它是否影响了你
I wonder what it's done to you.
黑暗神书只让我看到真相
The Darkhold only showed me the truth.
我能再拥有曾经失去的一切
Everything I lost can be mine again.
你想对阿美莉卡怎么样？
What do you want with America?
你想如何利用多重宇宙？
What do you want with the Multiverse?
我会离开这个现实
I'm going to leave this reality...
到能跟孩子在一起的那个现实
and go to one where I can be with my children.
旺达 你的孩子不是真的
Wanda, your children aren't real.
你用魔法创造了他们
You created them using magic.
每个母亲都是
That's what every mother does.
如果你知道…
If you knew...
有一个宇宙
there was a universe...
你在那里很幸福
where you were happy...
难道你不想去吗？
wouldn't you want to go there?
我现在很幸福
I am happy.
我最清楚什么叫自欺欺人
I know better than most what self-deception looks like.
你公然违反所有自然定律
What you're doing is a flagrant violation of every natural law...
如果夺走那孩子的能力 她必死无疑
and if you take that child's power, she won't survive.
我并不乐意伤害人 史蒂芬
I don't relish hurting anyone, Stephen.
但她不是孩子
But she's not a child.
她是超自然个体
She's a supernatural being.
那么强大的能力足以破坏各个世界
Such raw power could wreak havoc on this and other worlds.
她牺牲小我…
Her sacrifice...
能完成大我
would be for the greater good.
你别想被印在便当盒上了
Well, you can kiss the lunch box goodbye,
那是我们敌人用的借口
'cause that's the kind of justification our enemies use.
那是你的借口吗…
Is it the one you used...
当你给萨诺斯时间宝石？
when you gave Thanos the Time Stone?
那是战争 我是不得已的
That was a war, and I did what I had to do.
你破坏规则 成为英雄
You break the rules and become a hero.
我却变成敌人
I do it, and I become the enemy.
好像不太公平
That doesn't seem fair.
现在要怎样？
What happens now?
回到卡玛泰姬
Return to Kamar-Taj...
准备在日落前交出阿美莉卡查维兹
and prepare to hand over America Chavez by sundown.
和平移交
Peacefully.
然后…
After that...
你再也不会见到我
You'll never see me again.
不然呢？
And if we don't?
来找她的就不会是旺达
Then it won't be Wanda who comes for her.
而是绯红女巫
It will be the Scarlet Witch.
绯红女巫
The Scarlet Witch.
旺达不见了
Wanda's gone.
她取得黑暗神书 黑暗神书控制了她
She's got the Darkhold, and the Darkhold has her.
绯红女巫拥有深不可测的魔法
The Scarlet Witch is a being of unfathomable magic.
她能随意改写现实
She can rewrite reality as she chooses...
不是将统治宇宙
and is prophesized to either rule...
就是摧毁宇宙
or annihilate the cosmos.
她用意志力控制了整座小镇
She took over a whole town using her mind.
如果获得阿美莉卡的能力
If she gets America's power...
她就能征服多重宇宙
she could enslave the entire Multiverse.
所以你求助的对象
So, the person you went to ask for help...
不但知道我在哪里
and told exactly where I am...
也想杀我？
is the person that's trying to kill me?
对
Yeah.
立刻暂停教学 武装学员
Suspend teaching at once and arm the students.
卡玛泰姬必须转为抗敌要塞
Kamar-Taj must now become a fortress.
哇
Wow.
是香港和伦敦至圣所的大师
It's the masters of the Hong Kong and London Sanctums.
能再一次跟您并肩拚死 是我的光荣
It's an honor to court death alongside you once again.
也是我们的光荣
The honor is ours.
对于至尊魔法师的要求 使命必达
Whatever the Sorcerer Supreme asks of us, it shall be done.
待命魔法师 跟我来
Extra duty men, follow me.
这是古老习俗
It's ancient custom.
小心说话
Choose your words wisely.
多重宇宙的命运可能因此改变
The fate of the Multiverse may depend on it.
了解
Got it.
不要有压力
No pressure, then.
全是为了一个你昨天认识的孩子
All this for a child you met yesterday.
旺达 你有权利生气
Wanda, you are justifiably angry.
你不得不做出莫大的牺牲
You had to make terrible sacrifices.
我在爱人的头上炸出一个洞
I blew a hole through the head of the man I loved...
结果却毫无意义
and it meant nothing.
不要跟我谈牺牲 史蒂芬斯特兰奇
Do not speak to me of sacrifice, Stephen Strange.
如果你给我我要的
If you give me what I want...
我就送你去能和克里斯汀一起的世界
I'll send you to a world where you can be with Christine.
强大的卡玛泰姬会联合对抗你
The full might of Kamar-Taj stands against you.
就防守位置 准备
Defensive positions, now!
休想进入这些圣地
Do not dare to enter these sacred grounds.
你不知道我有多讲理
You have no idea just how reasonable I have been.
对
Yeah.
死亡之书 自称女巫
Book of the Damned, calling yourself a witch,
召唤怪兽绑架少女
conjuring creatures to abduct a kid...
我不觉得那叫讲理
I don't exactly call that being reasonable.
派那些禽兽去追她 算我仁慈
Sending those creatures after her instead of myself was mercy.
尽管你如此虚伪 又羞辱我
And in spite of your hypocrisies, and insults...
我一直求你不要从中作梗
I have begged you to safely get out of my way.
你磨光了我的耐性
You have exhausted my patience...
但我很希望你了解 即使是现在
but I do hope you understand that even now...
即将发生的事
what's about to happen...
这就是我…
this is me...
在讲理
being reasonable.
撑住
Hold!
搞定
Nailed it.
强化防护盾
Reinforce the shield.
Reinforce the shield!
强化防护盾
她想干扰他们的想法
She's trying to get in their heads.
魔法师 巩固意志
Sorcerers, fortify your mind!
快跑
Run.
防护盾失效
The shield is down!
发射
Fire!
赞
Yes!
找掩护
Take cover!
任意发射
Fire at will!
撤退
Fall back.
王！
Wong!
快离开
Get out of here!
快走…
Go, go.
快走
Go!
阿美莉卡
America...
想要那个女孩 先过我这一关
You want the girl, you'll have to go through me.
好
Fine.
我们得马上带你离开
We gotta get you out of here. Now.
王 怎么回事？
Wong, what happened?
卡玛泰姬沦陷了
Kamar-Taj has fallen.
反射
Reflections.
她利用反射影像 盖起来
She's using the reflections. Cover them.
你牺牲那些生命
You gave all those lives...
只为了不让我接近我的孩子
just to keep me from my children.
是你杀了那些人
You took those lives.
不能让你进入多重宇宙
You cannot be allowed to cross into the Multiverse.
我不是怪物 史蒂芬
I'm not a monster, Stephen.
我是母亲
I'm a mother.
旺达 你没有孩子
Wanda, you have no children.
他们不存在
They don't exist.
他们存在
Oh, but they do.
在其他每个宇宙里
In every other universe.
我知道他们在
I know they do.
因为我会梦到他们
Because I dream of them...
每天晚上
every night.
我们表演出来
We're gonna show it.
妈 你看我们
Mom, watch us. Mom!
跑远一点 回去…
Go long. Got it! All right, go on back, go on back.
好 不要…
All right, yeah. Don't...
梦到我的宝贝儿子
Of my boys.
比利 你敢！
Billy, don't you dare! No!
梦到我们一起生活
Of our life together.
-这里　-赞
-Here. -Yes!
然后回到前面
And then back to front.
回到前面
Back to front.
我能吃吗？
Can I have some?
拜托啦
Please?
-你们好了吗？　-没关系
-Are you guys ready? -It's okay.
我爱你 妈
I love you, Mom.
每天晚上
Every night...
相同的梦
the same dream.
每天早晨
And every morning...
相同的恶梦
the same nightmare.
要是你找到他们呢？
What if you reach them?
另一个你会如何？
What happens to the other you?
他们的母亲会怎样？
What happens to their mother?
你还好吗？
You okay?
你救了我
You saved me.
希望如此
I hope so.
你竟然没吐
Surprised you didn't puke.
这不是我第一趟怪异之旅
It's not my first weird trip, kid.
所以 这是纽约 在多重…
So, this is New York in the Multi...
对
Yep.
来了
There it is.
讨厌
Crap.
别闹了
Cut it out.
对 你伤痕累累
Yeah, you got pretty dinged up.
再帮你修补
We'll get you fixed.
好 阿美莉卡
All right, America.
你得打开一个入口 马上回去
You gotta open a portal and get us back there right now.
我不会
I don't know how.
你刚刚做到了
You just did it.
不是故意的
Not on purpose.
王单独对抗旺达 我是他唯一的希望
Wong is back there alone with Wanda, and I'm the only hope he has.
我不能控制…　-你一定可以
-I can't control my powers... -You must be able to control it somehow.
就连我都可以…
Even I could...
抱歉
Sorry.
这个宇宙的你呢？
Well, what about this universe's version of you?
或许她能控制她的能力
Maybe she could control her powers.
这个宇宙没有我
This universe doesn't have a me.
-什么？　-全都没有
-What? -None of them do.
你怎么知道？
But how do you know that?
因为我找过了
'Cause I've looked.
我也从来没做过梦
And 'cause I never dream.
没关系 小鬼
That's okay, kid.
就算你带我回去 我也无力对抗旺达
And even if you could get me back there, I have no way of fighting Wanda.
维山帝之书呢？
What about The Book of Vishanti?
怎么样？
What about it?
你的分身认为它能阻止追我的东西
Other You thought it could stop whoever was after me.
我的分身真厉害 但他不在这里
Yeah, well, good for Other Me. He's not here, is he?
我不知道它在哪 除非有另一个分身
I don't know where it is, so unless there's another Other Me...
我们得去找…
We need to go find...
我的另一个分身
Other Other Me.
红灯通行？
We go on red?
记住多重宇宙旅行的第一个重点
Rule number one of Multiversal travel...
你什么都不懂
you don't know anything.
对
Right.
红灯了
It's red.
第二个重点是什么？
So, what's rule number two?
阿美莉卡？
America?
阿美莉卡
America!
第二个重点
Rule number two...
找吃的
find food.
最好是披萨 披萨球
Preferably pizza. Pizza balls.
你拿什么付钱？
How'd you pay for that?
免费的
It was free.
其实大多数宇宙的食物都免费
Food's free in most universes, actually.
你们竟然得付钱 好怪
It's weird you guys have to pay for it.
-喂 你没付钱　-对
-Hey! You didn't pay for that. -Right.
完蛋
Crap.
或许这里不能吃免钱
Maybe it's not free here.
披萨老爸一定收钱
Pizza Poppa always gets paid.
披萨老爸 放轻松 她只是个孩子
All right, Pizza Poppa, relax. She's just a kid...
-她饿了　-你才放轻松 奇异博士
-She was hungry. -Relax yourself, there, Doctor Strange.
这披风哪来的？
Where'd you get this cape from, anyway?
感觉很像真的
That feels authentic.
这不是披风 是斗篷 建议你放开
It's not a cape, it's a cloak, and I suggest you let go.
这套服装从奇异博物馆拿的吧？
You took this whole suit from the Strange Museum, didn't you?
-奇异博物馆　-你手脚不干净
-Strange Museum? -You're a taker.
赏你芥末酱
Why don't you take some mustard, huh?
走吧 趁机快溜
Come on. It's not permanent.
他几分钟后就会停止？
Like he'll stop in a few minutes?
大约三星期
About three weeks.
我们经过的那些宇宙…
Those universes we went through...
我们在其中一个是油漆吗？
were we paint in one of them?
对 最好别困在里面
Yeah, you don't wanna get stuck in there.
要吃东西很难
It's really hard to eat.
你到过几个宇宙？
How many universes have you been to?
72个
Seventy-two.
73 加上这个
Seventy-three, counting this one.
很多耶
That's a lot.
记忆信道 回放你的重要记忆
Memory Lane. Replay your significant memories...
（记忆信道）
优惠价实施中
...now at a discounted price.
我们记得 你才不会忘记
We remember so you don't forget.
好高级的餐厅
This is pretty fancy.
你得再申请一笔学贷吗？
Did you have to take out another student loan?
不用 我卖掉上周开刀的一颗肾脏
Nah. I just sold one of those kidneys that we operated on last week.
我要送你一样小礼物
So got you a little something.
恭喜
Congratulations.
这什么？
What is it?
打开来看看
Open it and see.
克里斯汀 这…
Christine, this is...
太棒了 谢谢
This is amazing. Thank you.
我们没空看这个
We don't have time for this.
记忆信道 回放你的重要记忆
Memory Lane. Replay your significant memories...
优惠价实施中
now at a discounted price.
我们记得 你才不会忘记
We remember so you don't forget.
这是哪里？
Where's this?
我家
Home.
我的两个妈妈
My moms.
阿美莉卡
America!
你说得对 这是浪费时间
You know, you were right. This is just a waste of time.
小鬼
Hey, kid.
那是你第一次打开入口吧？
That was the first time that you opened a portal, right?
不重要
Doesn't matter.
很重要 你失去了双亲
It does matter. You lost your parents.
我没失去她们 而是杀了她们
I didn't lose them. I killed them.
不 你没有 别这么想
No. No, you did not. Don't even think that.
我用无法控制的能力打开一个入口
Okay, I opened a portal with the powers I can't control...
送她们去一个致命的宇宙
and sent them to a random, probably deadly universe...
-无法逃脱　-听着
-with no way to escape. -Listen...
如果你妈妈跟女儿有一丁点像
if your moms are anything like their daughter...
她们就会活着
they survived.
相信你有一天会再见到她们
I'm sure you'll meet them again someday.
说得真好
Not bad.
谢谢
Thanks.
在你记忆银行里的女人
That woman in your memory bank thing...
是克里斯汀吧？
that was Christine, right?
对 那是克里斯汀
Yes, that was Christine.
-你怎么认得她？　-你的分身
-How do you know her? -From Other You.
他们在一起吗？
Were they together?
没有 他们不联络了
No, they didn't talk anymore.
他搞砸了
He blew it.
当然
Of course.
你跟克里斯汀的关系也搞砸了吗？
Did you blow it with your Christine?
对 我想是
Yes, I guess I did.
为什么？
Why?
说来复杂
Complicated.
比在多重宇宙被女巫追杀还复杂？
More complicated than being chased by a witch through the Multiverse?
对 是的
Yes, actually, it is.
（奇异博士奉献生命 击败萨诺斯）
（向地球最强英雄致上永恒谢意）
「奉献生命 击败萨诺斯」？
"Gave his life defeating Thanos"?
看吧？我们不全是坏蛋
Yeah. See? We're not all bad.
如果你的分身死了
If Other You's dead...
那谁是至圣所大师？
who's Master of the Sanctum?
糟糕
Oh, shit.
-你认识他？　-对 莫多
-You know him? -Yeah. Mordo.
他是最早让我进入卡玛泰姬的人
He was actually the first guy who let me into Kamar-Taj.
太好了
Oh, great.
后来他性情大变 誓言追杀我
And then he snapped and dedicated his life to trying to kill me.
噢
Oh.
太好了
Great.
我始终认为这一天会来
I always suspected this day would come.
是吗？
You did?
是
Yes.
因为你始终认为这一天会来
Because you always suspected this day would come.
我的兄弟
My brother.
好
All right.
进来
Come in...
跟我好好聊聊你的宇宙
and tell me everything about your universe.
红灯通行
You go on red.
你也挺令人佩服的
And you're quite formidable too, it seems.
多重宇宙旅人
A Multiversal traveler.
感谢你带奇异博士到安全之地
Well, thank the stars you brought Doctor Strange to safety.
逃离不代表安全
Well, just 'cause we jumped ship doesn't mean we're safe.
我们的旺达有能力召唤恶魔与怪物
Our Wanda has the ability to conjure demons and monsters...
在其他宇宙攻击阿美莉卡
to attack America in other universes.
她有黑暗神书？
So she has the Darkhold?
你知道黑暗神书？
Oh, you know of the Darkhold?
对 这个宇宙也有黑暗神书
Oh, yes. We have a Darkhold in this universe, too.
我这个至圣所守护着它
I guard it here in this Sanctum.
我们绝不让那危险武器落入敌人手中
We would never risk a weapon that dangerous falling into the wrong hands.
没错
Damn right.
如果你的黑暗神书跟我们的相似
But if your Darkhold is anything like ours, I'm afraid she can do far worse...
恐怕她能做的
than just summon monsters to come after you here.
会比召唤怪物来追你更邪恶
什么意思？
What do you mean?
书里有一个咒语
There is a spell contained within those pages...
会侵蚀灵魂
corrosive to the soul...
亵渎现实
a desecration of reality itself.
梦行
Dreamwalking.
梦行中的魔法师会将自己的意识
A Dreamwalking sorcerer projects their own consciousness...
从他们的宇宙投射至另一个
from their universe into another...
占有另一个自我的身体
possessing the body of an alternate self.
他们可能操纵邪恶的分身
They may puppeteer this unholy doppelganger
从远方追杀敌人
and pursue their enemies from afar.
这种占有并非现实之间的永久连结
The possession is not a permanent link between realities.
他们在短短的梦行时间里
But in the fleeting time they Dreamwalk...
能对入侵的宇宙造成无法挽回的伤害
they can do irreparable damage to the universe they invade.
所以你面对的或许不是恶魔
So it may not be a demon that you face.
可能是绯红女巫
It may be the Scarlet Witch.
她为何不一开始就用这招？
Why didn't she do that to begin with?
当时她还能讲理
Because that was her being reasonable.
你对维山帝之书了解多少？
What do you know of The Book of Vishanti?
黑暗神书的反论？
The Darkhold's antithesis?
它能给魔法师制敌所需的力量
It can give a sorcerer whatever power they need to vanquish their enemy.
我需要你帮我找到它
I need your help to get me to it.
抱歉 史蒂芬
I'm sorry, Stephen.
但我特别希望你了解
But I hope you, of all people, understand...
威胁我们现实的人不是旺达麦西莫夫
that it is not Wanda Maximoff who threatens our reality...
而是你们俩
it's the two of you.
-天啊　-茶里加了什么？
-Oh, God. -What was in that tea?
王八蛋
You son of a bitch.
尼山迪之沙
The Sands of Nisanti.
我只是在做你会做的
I'm only acting as you would.
她来了
She's coming.
儿子 该上床睡觉了
Boys, it's time for bed.
我们能再吃一点冰淇淋吗？
Can we have a little more ice cream?
-拜托啦　-拜托…
-Please. -Please, please, please!
-再一点点　-别逼妈妈当坏人
-A little more, please! -Hey, don't make Mom out to be the bad guy.
知道谁最棒吗？
You know who's the best?
-谁？　-2003年的老虎队
-Who? -2003 Tigers.
他们超逊的
They suck.
逊到爆
They're so bad they suck egg.
才怪 他们最棒了
No, they don't. They're the best.
-蠢蛋　-你才蠢
-Doofus. -Doofus 2.
你更蠢
Triple infinity doofus.
超级爆炸蠢
Infinity infinity googolplex quadruple doofus.
天下第一蠢到爆
Quintuple infinity... Crazy doofus.
宇宙无敌蠢
Googolplex doofus.
（生日）
妈
Mom?
什么事 亲爱的？
Yes, sweetheart?
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
丢垃圾
Just to take out the trash.
我们能给你看一样东西吗？
Can we show you something?
妈 快点
Mom, hurry, come on!
快来 很重要
Come on, it's important.
妈
Mom.
你一定喜欢
You'll like it.
来嘛 快点
Come on. Hurry up.
很重要
It's important.
妈 注意听
Okay, so, Mom, listen to this...
我先开始
I'm gonna start it.
不 我先开始
No, I wanna start it.
-我想先开始　-不 我先开始
-I wanna start it. I want to start! -No, I want to start!
-我先开始　-我先开始
-No! I want to start. -I want to start.
你们一起开始吧
Why don't you both start it...
不管是什么东西
whatever it is, together?
-好　-好
-Okay. -Okay.
-好了吗？　-好了
-You ready? -Yeah.
三、二、一 开始
Three, two, one, go.
我们爱吃冰淇淋
We like ice cream
就跟每个小朋友一样
Like every child should
如果吃了冰淇淋
And if we get some ice cream
我们保证会听话
We promise to be good
你没死
You're alive.
对
Yes.
可是很多人死了
But so many others were lost.
放了我
Set me free.
我必须摧毁那本书
I need to destroy the book.
不 不能由你动手
No. It cannot be you.
莎拉 不要…
Sara. No, no!
妈
Mom!
怎么了？
What happened?
-什么？　-你还好吗？
-What? -Are you okay?
比利 汤米
Okay. Billy, Tommy.
什么？
What?
不…
No, no, no.
我需要黑暗神书的咒语
I need the Darkhold's spells.
你是至尊魔法师
You are the Sorcerer Supreme.
把你知道的告诉我
Tell me what you know.
那你得杀了我 女巫
You're gonna have to kill me, witch.
不是杀你
Not you.
杀他们
Them.
旺达 住手
Wanda, stop.
旺达 求求你
Wanda, please!
那本黑暗神书是复本
The Darkhold was a copy!
复本？
A copy?
传说有一座山
Legend speaks of a mountain...
你要找的悲咒刻在山壁上
with the wretched spells you seek carved into its walls.
黑暗神书抄写在那里
It's there the Darkhold was transcribed.
万达格山
Mount Wundagore.
万达格？
Wundagore?
没人成功抵达过
No one has survived the journey.
也许我们会是例外
Perhaps we will be the exception.
喂！
Hey!
这个宇宙烂死了
This universe sucks.
斗篷呢？
Cloak?
喂
Hey.
喂 白袍哥
Hey, lab coat.
这是什么地方？
Where the hell are we?
我不知道你是谁 你想干什么
Look, I don't know who you are, or what you think you're trying to do here...
-但这种情况…　-谢谢
-but these situations don't usually... -Thank you.
对无名科学家通常不太妙
...work out well for the nameless scientists, so just...
克里斯汀？
Christine?
你好 史蒂芬
Hello, Stephen.
查维兹小姐
Miss Chavez.
回答你的问题
To answer your question...
这是一个高度戒备的研究机构
you are in a highly secure research facility.
你们俩 加上你有知觉的斗篷
The two of you, along with your sentient cloak...
是来接受监视与检验的
are here for surveillance and testing.
检验？
Testing?
对 你们是来自另一个宇宙的访客
Well, yes. You're visitors from another universe.
你们的磁迹可能有辐射
Your magnetic signatures could be radioactive...
你们可能有我们无法治疗的疾病
you may be carrying diseases we just don't have treatments for.
因此才用这些漂亮的聚碳酸酯鱼缸
Hence, these amazing polycarbonate fish bowls.
所以我该谢谢你啰？
I assume I have you to thank for these then?
是 我用尼山迪之沙研发出来的
Yes. I developed those using the Sands of Nisanti.
838史蒂芬的魔法遗迹之一
One of 838 Stephen's magical relics.
838史蒂芬？
838 Stephen?
那是我的机器人版还是…
Is that some kind of cyborg me, or...
我们宇宙是838
Our universe is 838,
你们宇宙的编号是616
and we've designated yours 616.
你们一定非常了解多重宇宙
You guys sure must know a lot about the Multiverse...
竟有人负责帮各个现实命名
if you got someone going around naming realities.
对
Yes.
就是我
Me.
我是巴克斯特基金会资深研究员
I'm a senior fellow with the Baxter Foundation...
专长是多重宇宙研究
and I specialize in Multiversal research.
你怎么会来这里工作？
So, how'd you end up working here?
不管这是哪里
Wherever here is.
我自愿加入
Well, I volunteered.
在你的葬礼上
At your funeral.
谢谢你去参加
Thank you for going.
你们的伤都很像 但不完全一样
Your injuries, they're similar, but they're not identical.
很有意思
It's fascinating.
（98.6%相符）
我们在这个宇宙是什么关系？
What were we to each other in this universe?
我们一直没搞清楚
We never quite figured that out.
是吗？
Yeah?
这算是我们的共同点
Well, that's something we got in common.
克里斯汀 你得让我们出去
Christine, you gotta let us out of here.
现在人人深陷危机
Everyone's in real danger.
我知道你不了解我
Look, I know you don't know me...
我也不想
And I don't want to.
在你的宇宙里我是你的谁都不要紧
Whatever I was to you in your universe does not matter.
为什么？
Why not?
因为你很危险 史蒂芬
Because you're dangerous, Stephen.
我的宇宙有人要抓那个女孩
Someone from my universe wants that girl...
对方会彻底摧毁这个地方
and she's gonna rip this place apart atom-by-atom...
不达目的绝不罢休
until she gets what she wants.
我不管你们来自复仇者联盟或神盾局
So I don't care if you're from the Avengers or S.H.I.E.L.D...
都不是
We're neither.
那是什么？
Well, what then?
九头蛇？
HYDRA?
光照会现在要见你
The Illuminati will see you now.
光照什么会？
The Illumi-what-y?
别让人伤害那个小鬼
Don't let anyone hurt that kid.
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
你不能直接带我们上去吗？
You couldn't portal us up there?
我的魔法只能带我们到这里
My magic can only take us so far.
秘术大师不该踏上…
Masters of the Mystic Arts weren't meant to tread...
万达格山禁地
upon the forbidden grounds of Wundagore.
很久以前 第一个恶魔西索恩
Eons ago, the first demon, Chthon, carved his dark magic...
将他的黑暗魔法刻在这座陵墓上
into this tomb.
同样的咒语后来抄入黑暗神书
These same spells were later transcribed into the Darkhold.
外人无法得知里面有什么无情怪物
There's no telling what soulless monstrosities lie within.
它们一直在等我
They've been waiting for me.
这不是陵墓
This isn't a tomb.
而是王座
It's a throne.
史蒂芬斯特兰奇
Stephen Strange...
你被召唤到光照会面前
you are now called before the Illuminati.
我卡尔莫多男爵 至尊魔法师特此…
I, Baron Karl Mordo, the Sorcerer Supreme, do hereby...
卡尔？
"Karl"?
卡特队长
Captain Carter.
第一位复仇者
The first Avenger.
布拉卡格博特贡
Blackagar Boltagon.
泰瑞根迷雾守护者 异人族国王
Keeper of the Terrigen Mists, the Inhuman king.
布拉卡格伏特加
Blackagar Boltagon?
我西迪威士忌
Hidigy hidithere.
惊奇队长 宇宙捍卫者
Captain Marvel. Defender of the cosmos.
以及当前最聪明的人
And the smartest man alive...
神奇四侠的李德理查斯
Reed Richards of the Fantastic Four.
你好 史蒂芬
Hello, Stephen.
神奇四侠
"Fantastic Four."
你们的歌有上排行榜吗？
Didn't you guys chart in the '60s?
抱歉 你觉得这是在搞笑吗？
I'm sorry, is this a joke to you?
有人头上有叉子
Well, there's a guy over there with a fork on his head...
对 有一点
so, yeah, a little bit.
你得感激黑蝠王没在谈话时插嘴
Be grateful Black Bolt doesn't engage you in conversation.
为什么？他有口臭吗？
Why? Does he have bad breath?
这个斯特兰奇比我们的更嚣张
This Strange is even more arrogant than ours.
不 只是更有活力
No, just more alive.
那是现在
For now.
史蒂芬 你来造成现实混乱与失稳
Stephen, your arrival here confuses and destabilizes reality.
你留下的冲击越大
The larger the footprint you leave behind,
对撞事件的风险就越大
the greater the risk of an Incursion.
对撞事件？
Incursion?
对撞事件就是两个宇宙的界线侵蚀
An Incursion occurs when the boundary between two universes erodes...
两者相撞
and they collide...
彻底摧毁其中之一或同归于尽
destroying one or both entirely.
你的分身创立了光照会
Your alternate self created the Illuminati...
要做其他人无法做的困难决定
to make difficult decisions that no one else could.
今天我们要决定如何处置你和那孩子
Today, we're here to determine what to do with you and the child.
在我们投票前
So, before we vote...
如果有认真的话想说 就趁现在
if you got anything serious to say, now's the time.
有
Yeah, I do.
如果你们担心对撞事件
If it's Incursions you're worried about...
你们真以为我的威胁比绯红女巫大？
do you seriously think I'm a bigger threat than the Scarlet Witch?
如果小女巫决定梦行 我们能对付她
Oh, we can handle your little witch if she decides to Dreamwalk.
你们没办法 除非给我维山帝之书
No. No, you cannot. Not unless you give me The Book of Vishanti.
多谢关心 史蒂芬
We appreciate your concern, Stephen,
但我们担心的不是绯红女巫
but it's not the Scarlet Witch that we fear.
根据经验 多重宇宙最大的危险是…
From our experience, the greatest danger to the Multiverse, it turns out...
奇异博士
is Doctor Strange.
等等 你们的奇异博士？
Wait. Your Doctor Strange?
击败萨诺斯而死的地球最强英雄？
Earth's mightiest hero who died defeating Thanos?
我们应该告诉他真相
We should tell him the truth.
我们最后一位成员
Our final member...
查尔斯泽维尔教授
Professor Charles Xavier.
什么真相？
What truth?
我们的斯特兰奇不是那么死的
That's not how our Strange died.
你在想现在会怎么样
You're wondering what happens now.
不是
No.
我已经接受了
That I've already accepted.
我真正想知道的是
But I do wonder...
你能逼阿美莉卡送你去任何宇宙
when you could force America to send you to any universe you want...
为何还要把她的能力占有己有？
why take her power for your own?
你明知那样会害死她
You know it would kill her.
为了保护比利和汤米
For Billy and Tommy, to protect them.
要是他们生病呢？
What if they get sick?
在无限的多重宇宙 每种病都有解药
In the infinite Multiverse, there's a cure for every illness.
每个问题都有解决办法
A solution to every problem.
我不愿再失去他们
I won't lose them again.
尽管尝试 但你控制不了一切
Try as you might, Wanda, you cannot control everything.
我可以
But I can.
看看你四周
Look around you.
它就刻在石头上
It's carved in stone.
我原本就该统治一切
I was meant to rule everything.
但那不是我要的
But that's not what I want.
我只要我的宝贝儿子
I just want my boys.
牺牲掉一个孩子的命？
At the cost of a child's life?
即使不能和心爱的人在一起
Is there no peace in knowing that even though you can't be with the ones you love...
你们还是在某些世界里相聚
there are worlds where you are together?
那样还不够吗？
Is that not enough?
不够
No.
我们的斯特兰奇并未因击败萨诺斯而死
Our Strange did not die defeating Thanos.
当时我们在作战
We were at war.
其他人团结起来阻止萨诺斯
While the rest of us banded together to try to stop Thanos...
史蒂芬却一如往常选择单独行动
Stephen, as always, chose to go it alone.
他求助于黑暗神书
He turned to the Darkhold...
开始梦行
began Dreamwalking...
希望答案就在多重宇宙里
in hopes that our salvation might lie in the Multiverse.
结果你猜怎么样？
And guess what?
并没有 但他仍一意孤行
It didn't. But he kept doing it anyway.
一天晚上你召集我们
One night, you called us all together...
坦承你一直在梦行
confessed that you had been Dreamwalking...
你说的是「情况已经失控」
and in your words, "Things had gotten out of hand."
你从未告诉我们详细经过
You never told us the details of what had happened...
只有你不慎引发对撞事件
only that you had inadvertently triggered an Incursion.
朋友 你造成另一个宇宙毁灭
You, our friend, had caused the annihilation of another universe.
那个现实中的每个人都死了
Everyone in that reality died.
每一个人
Everyone.
史蒂芬否认黑暗神书的邪恶
Stephen renounced the Darkhold's evil...
帮助我们找到维山帝之书
and helped us find The Book of Vishanti...
我们共同把它当武器 击败萨诺斯
a weapon we did use together to defeat Thanos.
但还剩一个最终的威胁
But one final threat remained.
我会怀念你的 朋友
I shall miss you, my friend.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你们告诉克里斯汀了吗？
Did you tell Christine?
有
Yes.
那尊雕像…
The statue...
那尊雕像呢？
What about the statue?
你们立了一尊雕像
You built a statue.
世界需要英雄
The world needs heroes.
我们做出困难的决定
We made the difficult choice
因为我们知道斯特兰奇的能耐
because we knew what our Strange was capable of.
或许是每个奇异博士的能耐
What, perhaps, every Doctor Strange is capable of.
大楼遭人闯入
The building's been breached.
不会吧 真天才
No shit, genius.
显示安全状态
Status report on sentries.
停在…
Stop where you...
回来
Get back!
停在原地
Stop where you are...
她要去找那孩子
She's heading for the child.
看好他 我们回来再投票
Watch him. We'll vote on our return.
史蒂芬 要是你逃离这房间
Stephen, should you manage to escape this chamber...
一定要引导阿美莉卡查维兹
you must guide America Chavez.
你在说什么东西？
What the hell are you saying?
救那个女孩 去找维山帝之书
Save the girl and get to The Book of Vishanti.
那本书在这里？
What? You have the book here?
对 你建立了一个中继点
Yes. You built a waypoint.
查尔斯 我们不能相信他
Charles, we cannot trust him.
我想可以
I believe we can.
有人一时迷途
Just because someone stumbles and loses their way...
不代表他们会永远迷失
doesn't mean they're lost forever.
我们看看你是哪种奇异博士
We will see what kind of Doctor Strange you are.
谢谢
Thank you.
（安全漏洞 启动封锁程序）
外力入侵
Perimeter breakdown.
全体卫兵出动
All sentries engage.
所有人都出去
Everybody out.
-入侵者接近　-快点
-Intruder approaching. -Now!
是旺达
It's Wanda.
（D24室 采取手动超控）
奥创命令你停止
Ultron commands you to halt.
奥创命令你…
Ultron commands...
（压力密封解除）
快点…她来了
Hurry, hurry! She's coming!
糟了
Oh, no.
旺达 住手
Wanda, stop.
你掌控了一个无辜女人
You've possessed an innocent woman,
但还是能悬崖勒马
but you can still do the right thing.
放了她
Let her go.
求求你
Please.
我自己有小孩 能体会你的痛苦
I have children of my own. I understand your pain.
他们的母亲还活着吗？
Is their mother still alive?
是
Yes.
很好
Good.
会有人留下来抚养他们
There will be someone left to raise them.
旺达 黑蝠王嘴巴张开就能摧毁你
Wanda, Black Bolt could destroy you with one whisper from his mouth.
什么嘴巴？
What mouth?
带我去找维山帝之书
Take me to The Book of Vishanti,
我们一起对抗她
so that we can fight her together.
你没资格发号施令
You are in no position to give orders.
等他们回来 我这一票将终结程序
My vote will conclude these proceedings when they return.
你还没受够吗？
Haven't you had enough?
我可以陪你玩一整天
Oh, I could do this all day.
滚出我的宇宙
Get the hell out of my universe!
他们不会回来了
They're not coming back.
你刚刚表明要杀死你朋友
And you just cast your vote now to kill your friends.
那以前也没为你带来困扰
Not that that ever bothered you before.
在我的宇宙 你恨我
You know, you hated me where I came from.
我敢说你在这里也偷偷恨我 兄弟
And I bet secretly, my brother, you hated me here.
你一定嫉妒死了
You must've been so jealous.
知道吗？
Do you know what?
听到我如此堕落 你一定乐坏了
I bet you were thrilled when you heard I'd been corrupted.
你大概一开始就给了我黑暗神书
Hell, you probably gave me the Darkhold to begin with...
你完全不了解这个宇宙
You know nothing of this universe!
你杀死史蒂芬斯特兰奇才能掌控至圣所
I know that killing Stephen Strange was your ticket to getting the Sanctum...
成为至尊魔法师
to becoming Sorcerer Supreme...
加入你那个小丑马戏团 光照会
and to joining your little circus of clowns, the Illuminati.
我准备好…
I'm ready...
投下我这一票了
to cast my vote now.
我想我开始懂了
I think I'm beginning to understand...
你的莫多为何不太喜欢你
why your Mordo didn't like you very much!
你被封死了
You're sealed shut!
后退
Okay. Get back.
哇
Whoa.
够了
Enough!
拜托救救我
Help me. Please.
旺达麦西莫夫 你的意志被分身挟持
Wanda Maximoff, your mind is being held hostage by your alternate self.
抓住我的手
Grab my hand.
或许 如果我把你从瓦砾中拉出来
Perhaps, if I can pull you from under the rubble...
咒语就会破除
the spell will break.
你们还好吗？
Hey! You all right?
没事吧？
You okay?
嗨
Hey.
-还好吗？　-还好
-You all right? -Yeah.
嗨
Hey.
她修补好它了
She fixed him.
-谢谢　-别客气
-Thank you. -Yeah.
泽维尔说我建了维山帝之书的中继点
Xavier said I built a waypoint to The Book of Vishanti.
你能带我们去吗？
Can you take us there?
我怎么能相信你？
How am I supposed to trust you?
我知道怎么回事 很遗憾他那么做
I know what happened, and I'm sorry for what he did...
相信我 维山帝之书是唯一的办法
but believe me, The Book of Vishanti is the only way.
对 你的办法
Yeah. Your way.
你口气很像我的史蒂芬
You sound a lot like my Stephen right now.
他非掌控大局不可 结果害死一万亿人
He had to be the one holding the knife, and then that knife killed a trillion people.
这个史蒂芬不一样
This Stephen is different.
真的
He is.
其他的史蒂芬都不重要
It doesn't matter about all the other Stephens.
你跟他们不同
You're not like them.
聪明的小鬼
Smart kid.
手伸出来
Give me your hand.
别让我后悔
Do not make me regret this.
不会的
I won't.
-可以走了吗？　-跟我来
-Okay, can we go now? -Yeah, follow me.
这条隧道通往哪里？
Where's that tunnel go?
河底
Under the river.
快走…
Go, go, go!
（警告 防爆门）
她去哪里？
Where did she go?
我警告过你
I warned you.
旺达分身 如果你在里面
Other Wanda, if you're in there...
憋住气
hold your breath.
-她死了吗？　-没有 争取时间而已
-Did you kill her? -No, just bought us some time.
维山帝之书在里面
The Book's through here.
只有史蒂芬打开过
But only Stephen's ever opened it.
可恶
Shit.
专属我的魔法 只有我知道
An enchantment that's specific to me, something only I would know.
-等等 史蒂芬　-快想
-Wait. Stephen. -Come on.
快点
Come on.
史蒂芬
Stephen.
对
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
Sure.
芝麻开门
Open sesame.
下来 小鬼
Come on, kid.
你可以
You got this.
我们可以
We got this.
对
Yeah.
没事吧？
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
这是裂隙接点 宇宙之间的空间
This is the Gap Junction, the space between universes.
好 维山帝之书
All right, Book.
给我我需要的
Give me what I need.
-不　-不
-No! -No!
我的儿子
My boys.
这不是你孩子要的
This isn't what your children would want.
他们永远不会知道
They'll never know.
或许不会
Maybe not.
但你会
But you will.
不会吧
Oh, no.
惨了
Oh, crap.
这个现实好像自己瓦解
It's like this reality collapsed in on itself.
对
Yeah.
或两个现实相撞
Or two realities collided.
快走
Come on.
阿美莉卡时间不多了
America doesn't have long.
那我们要去哪？
So where are we going?
如果这宇宙还有一个至圣所
Well, if there's still a sanctum in this universe...
那可能有另一个我的分身的分身
then there might be another Other Other Me...
那是我们救她回来的最佳机会
and that's our best shot of getting back to her.
我明白你们为何这么担心对撞事件
Well, I can see why you guys were so worried about Incursions.
不管发生过什么事
Whatever happened...
这个宇宙的你并未尽力阻止它
this universe's you didn't do a very good job of stopping it.
我会告诉他你这么说
I'll tell him you said that.
有人吗？
Hello?
站住别动
Stop where you are.
你怎么来的？
How did you get here?
歪打正着
By accident.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你是什么？
What are you?
我是我们之一
I'm just one of us.
来自多重宇宙？
From the Multiverse?
没错
That's right.
提出证明
Prove it.
我们有个妹妹
We had a sister.
唐娜
Donna.
可是她…
But she...
小时候就死了
She died when we were kids.
怎么死的？
How?
我们在结冰的湖上玩耍
We were playing on a frozen lake and...
她掉进湖里
she fell through the ice.
我没办法救她
I couldn't save her.
听起来没错
Sounds about right.
但我们不谈那件事 对吧？
But we don't talk about that, do we?
对 不谈
No, we don't.
我想你的现实并非一直如此
Suppose your reality wasn't always like this.
我猜本来跟你的一样 直到…
I suspect it was somewhat like yours until...
直到？
Until?
直到我迷失
Until I lost.
因为谁？
To whom?
你想怎么样？
What do you want?
我想回家
I just want to get home.
相信我
Yeah? Believe me...
长久以来我一直想离开这里
I've been trying to leave this place for a long time.
黑暗神书
Darkhold.
你在这个宇宙里守护黑暗神书？
You guard the Darkhold in this universe?
对
Yeah.
有充分的理由
For good reason.
这是个开始
That's a start.
我能利用它 帮我跟我的宇宙沟通
I could use it. It could help me to communicate with my universe.
小心
Careful.
黑暗神书会造成严重伤亡
The Darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
不是我无情
I don't mean to be callous...
还能有多严重的伤亡呢？
but how much of a heavier toll is there left to exact?
不只是对它的现实
Not just on its reality.
还有对它的读者
On its reader.
很遗憾你救不了你的宇宙
Look, I'm sorry you couldn't save your universe...
或许你能帮忙救我的
but maybe you could help to save mine.
你幸福吗 史蒂芬？
Are you happy, Stephen?
什么？
What?
你幸福吗 史蒂芬？
Are you happy, Stephen?
这个问题是…
It's the question that...
克里斯汀帕尔默
Christine Palmer...
在她婚礼上问我的
asked me at her wedding.
我说我当然很幸福
I said, "Yes, of course I'm happy.
我是力量强大的魔法师
"I'm a sorcerer with the power of gods.
怎么会不幸福？
What man wouldn't be happy?"
然后我回到这间该死的鬼屋
And then I came back to this goddamn haunted house...
坐下来
sat down...
想着我为何说谎
and wondered why I'd lied.
我根本无意让这一切发生
I never meant for any of this to happen.
我在寻找一个不同的世界
I was looking for a world where things were different.
在那里我有克里斯汀 我很幸福
Where I had Christine, where I was happy.
但我没找到
But I didn't find it.
只发现更多的我们
All I found were more of us.
于是我帮那些史蒂芬一个忙
So I did those Stephens a favor.
你是否做过那个坠落的梦
You ever had that dream where you're falling...
彷佛你被推下高楼？
as if you've been pushed off a tall building?
那应该是我
That was probably me.
黑暗神书会造成严重伤亡
The Darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
好
Okay.
这样更有理由别用它 交给我
All the more reason to give it a rest and let me have it.
不如这样吧
Here's the deal.
我让你用黑暗神书 你给我克里斯汀
I'll let you use the Darkhold if you give me your Christine.
唉
Yeah.
我想她不会同意
I don't think she's gonna go for that.
是吗？
No?
我也觉得不会
Didn't think so.
等着 我们来了
Hang on, we're coming.
你要怎么用黑暗神书？
What are you doing with the Darkhold?
你要梦行吗？
Are you going to Dreamwalk?
比梦行再多一点
It's a little bit more than just Dreamwalking.
你们斯特兰奇都一样
All you Stranges, you're the same.
我知道
I know.
你说得对
You're right.
我们都一样
We are all the same.
但现在那孩子需要我
But right now, that kid needs me.
没有你帮忙我绝对做不到
And I can't do any of this without your help.
我在梦行时 请你保护我的身体
While I'm under, I need you to protect my body...
以免他们因为我擅闯而攻击我
in case they attack me for trespassing.
他们是谁？
Who's "they"?
地狱亡者的灵魂
The souls of the damned.
好
Okay.
不是有一个你必须住在那个宇宙
But doesn't a version of you need to live in that universe...
你才能梦行进去吗？
so that you can Dreamwalk into them?
谁说他们必须是活的？
Who said they had to be living?
史蒂芬斯特兰奇
Stephen Strange...
占有亡者遗体是禁忌
possessing a dead body is forbidden.
禁忌
Forbidden.
擅闯者
Trespasser!
停止梦行 否则就面对永恒的后果
Cease your Dreamwalk, or face the eternal consequences.
史蒂芬
Stephen!
他们要把我拉下去
They're pulling me down.
史蒂芬
Stephen!
撑下去…
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
你在哪里？
Where are you?
波歌利亚火盆
The Brazier of Bom'Galiath.
滚回地狱去吧
Go back to hell.
史蒂芬
Stephen.
我在这里
I've got you.
你是秘术大师
You're a Master of the Mystic Arts.
他们是幽魂
They're spirits.
利用他们
Use them.
不！
No!
来啊
Come on!
斯特兰奇
Strange!
竟然梦行 你这个伪君子
Dreamwalking. You hypocrite!
这次想要杀了我
This time, it's gonna take more than killing me...
不能只杀了这个
to kill me.
杀人凶手…
Murderer! Murderer!
我根本不想知道
I don't even wanna know.
不！
No!
-不　-不
-No! -No!
她挣脱了
She's breaking free!
困住她
Hold her!
斯特兰奇 利用阿美莉卡的力量
Strange, take America's power!
没别的办法了
There's no other way.
对
Yeah.
这是唯一的办法
This is the only way.
是我 在我分身的身体里
It's me in Other Me's body.
你是来夺走我的能力吧？
You're here to take my power, aren't you?
抢在旺达之前
Before Wanda can.
没关系
It's okay.
我现在懂了
I understand now.
不 阿美莉卡
No, America.
我是来告诉你要相信自己
I've come here to tell you to trust yourself.
相信你的能力
Trust your power.
我们就要这样阻止她
That's how we stop her.
我无法控制它
I can't control it. I...
可以 你可以
Yes, you can.
你始终都可以
You have been all along.
每次你打开入口
Every time you opened a portal,
就送我们到该去的地点
you sent us exactly where we needed to go.
那第一次怎么说？
What about the first time?
那也带领你到现在这一刻
Even that led you to this moment...
你即将痛宰那个女巫
when you're gonna kick that witch's ass.
我帮你
I've got you.
我击败不了你
I can't beat you.
那就给你想要的
So I'll give you what you want.
比利 汤米
Billy. Tommy.
妈咪 是女巫
Mommy! It's the witch!
你做了什么？
What have you done?
-妈　-妈咪
-Mom! -Mommy!
等等 儿子
Wait! Boys!
没事…
It's okay, it's okay. It's okay.
我是你们妈妈
I'm your mother!
不准靠近他们
Get away from them.
妈
Mom!
不
No.
还没
Not yet.
妈咪
Mommy!
别碰我们妈妈
Get away from our mom!
-你不是我们的真妈妈　-住手
-You're not our real mom! -Hey, boys. Stop.
-拜托…　-滚出我们家
-Please. Please. -Get out of our house!
儿子 住手
Boys, stop it.
你不是我们妈妈　-出去
-You're not our mom! -Get out!
-走开　-快走
-Go away! -Go!
住手
Stop it!
拜托别伤害我们
Please don't hurt us.
求求你
Please.
我绝对不会伤害你们
I would never hurt you.
绝对不会
Never.
我绝对不会伤害任何人
I would never hurt anyone.
我不是怪物
I'm not a monster.
我是…
I'm a...
I'm...
对不起
I'm sorry.
妈
Mom!
-你还好吗？　-嗨
-Are you okay? -Hi.
嗨 没事
Hi. Okay.
我没事
I'm okay.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
-妈 不要去　-妈 不要
-Mom, don't go. Don't go. -No, Mom. Don't.
-没关系　-妈
-It's okay. -Mom.
没关系
It's okay. It's okay.
有人会爱他们的
Know that they'll be loved.
现在呢？
What now?
离开这里
Get out of here.
我再去找你
I'll find you.
我们该走了 快
We have to go. Now!
我打开了黑暗神书
I opened the Darkhold.
必须把它阖上
I have to close it.
没有人会再受黑暗神书诱惑了
No one will ever be tempted by the Darkhold again.
你还好吗？
You all right?
-结束了吗？　-对
-Is it over? -Yeah.
阿美莉卡没事吧？
Is America okay?
她正要过来接我们
She's on her way here to get us.
旺达呢？
Wanda?
没有
No.
她摧毁了每个宇宙的黑暗神书
So she destroyed the Darkhold in every universe.
她做对了
She did the right thing.
没错
Yeah, she did.
你的宇宙是什么样子？
What's your universe like?
非常美
It's very beautiful.
真希望我能带你去看
I wish I could show you.
我很想去
I'd really like that.
-但我该走了　-对
-But I have to go. -Yeah.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
太可惜了
It's too bad, though.
原本可能会有一次对撞事件
Could've been one hell of an Incursion.
我爱你
I love you.
我在每个宇宙都爱你
I love you in every universe.
我也想关心一个人或有人来关心我
It's not that I don't wanna care for someone or have someone care for me.
只是…
It's just...
我很害怕
I get scared.
是
Yeah.
是啊
面对你的恐惧
Face your fears...
奇异博士
Doctor Strange.
这怎么比多重宇宙入口还要难？
How is this so much harder than a Multiversal portal?
她需要放慢脚步 更有耐心
She needs to slow down and be more patient.
让我想起另一个学生
Reminds me of another student I knew.
感觉如何？
How you feeling?
为何这么问？
Why do you ask?
你用黑暗神书梦行到自己的尸体里
You used the Darkhold to Dreamwalk into your own corpse.
对喔
Yeah, right, that.
没事
Fine.
我倒是想问你一件事
But I do wanna ask you something.
你幸福吗？
Are you happy?
这问题…
That's a...
有意思
interesting question.
原本以为拯救世界会获得幸福
You'd think that saving the world would get you there...
并没有
but it doesn't.
有时我忍不住会幻想其他宇宙的生活
Sometimes, I do wonder about my other lives.
但我还是很感恩在这里
Yet I remain grateful in this one.
即使有种种苦难
Even with its tribulations.
至少我们不必独自面对
At least we don't have to go through it alone, huh?
没错
No, we don't.
等一下
Wait.
你好
'Sup?
'Sup.
我创造了一些火花
Made some sparks.
很好
Great.
你的双亲会很骄傲
Your parents would be proud.
希望以后她们能看到
I hope you'll get to show 'em one day.
史蒂芬
Stephen.
我很高兴落入你的宇宙
I'm glad I fell into your universe.
我也很高兴 小鬼
So am I, kid.
我也很高兴
So am I.
奇异博士2：失控多重宇宙
奇异博士？
Doctor Strange?
有什么事吗？
Can I help you?
你引发对撞事件
You caused an Incursion...
我们必须解决
and we're gonna fix it.
除非你怕了
Unless you're afraid.
一点也不怕
Not in the least.
（奇异博士将再回归）
结束了
It's over！